Junior Network Engineer

Junior Network Engineer - University of Maryland Orthopaedic and Rehabilitation Institute

Laurel, MD - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/2c244abc8faa2f3d

/CAREER SUMMARY

To pursue a career that is challenging yet rewarding while exhibiting strong analytical, customer service, problem solving, negotiation, teaching, and organizational skills; Adept administrator with 11 years of experience implementing processes to create more efficient organizations in the areas of administration, human resources, and operations. Self-motivated leader with ability to research, plan, coordinate, problem solve, and execute complex and multiple tasks in fast-paced environments; Strong analytical, interpersonal and team building skills; excellent oral and written communication skills; Proficient with the Microsoft Office

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Network Engineer

University of Maryland Orthopaedic and Rehabilitation Institute - April 2015 to Present

Internship with the Senior Network Engineer of various UMMS locations; Trouble shooting LAN and WAN connections, Layer 2 and Layer 3 routing (RIP, EIGRP, OSPF, BGP and MPLS), stacking and configuring multiple switches (layer 2 and layer 3) with Cisco switches and routers; manages and understands the important issues that have connections with administering and maintaining business infrastructure, including network connectivity, net access, email and other task with network connection; understands the subjects associated in administering as well as maintaining business WAN; perform switch audits using Fluke Networks Link Runner

Senior Financial Control Specialist

Works with UMMS - September 2006 to Present

Oversees the financial payment functions within the department and serve as departmental extension for Accounts Payable as they relate to processing of transactions. Serves as a liaison as it relates to vendor payment disputes; Executes, communicates and enforce changes in department procedures to staff and UMMS departments; Works with UMMS facilities to organize and maintain system processes as it relates to Accounts Payable; Works with Department Managers at all facilities with various specific needs including the analysis of the budget variance issues; Assists them in understanding PMM system and transaction processing issues; Offers guidance and direction to assist accounts payable staff when required; Assists Medical System departments and Vendors in understanding Accounts Payable policies and procedures and the procurement process; Communicates to the respective Medical System departments and vendors regarding invoice price, quantity, item type or other discrepancies and clarifies, resolve or obtains information in accordance with departmental procedures; Works with Purchasing and Receiving to resolve invoice discrepancy issues and resolve routine vendor request or questions concerning payment. Under general direction, leads and implements accounts payable performance improvement initiatives; Inputting exception hours into a database; respond to customer concerns, research billing status, and resolve customer concerns.

Administrative Assistant III

Patient Placement and Resource Allocation - September 2003 to November 2006

Perform diversified administrative duties and serve as AAIII and Referral Coordinator to the Sr. Director of Patient Placement and Resource Allocation, Staffing and Resource Office, Infection Control, Respiratory

Therapy, Wound Care, Employee Health, Psychiatry, Ethics Committee, Pharmacy and Case Management departments. Duties include but are not limited to:

Provide administrative and technical support for the Director and various departments; provide organization and expedite office support while providing administrative instructions in the absence of the Director / Supervisor; Prepare and review a variety of materials to make necessary corrections and recommendations for review and approval in accordance with departmental procedures; Act as Staffing Coordinator in the absence of the Administrative Staffing Coordinator Assistant, Schedule conferences and meetings with appropriate accommodations and locations, Attend Ethics Committee staff meetings for note taking /minutes; prepare final formal submission; Submit inpatient referrals for approval or denial; secure location for all incoming patient; Coordinate and communicate admission details and patient demographics to inpatient rehabilitation units; Contact facilities and process forms of patients' transitions to other levels of care in the absence of the supervisor; Monthly tracking of professional licensures (timely renewals, expired licenses and disciplinary actions) for monthly Managers report for all licensed staff (Nurses, Respiratory Therapy, Dieticians, Dentistry, etc.); Create and prepare monthly surgical letters per surgeon indication of surgical site infections or non-infection for Infection Control Coordinator; Update Healthstream (a learning management system) with mandatory annual PPD/tuberculosis for employees; Submit requests for Interpreter Services as well as preparing and maintaining invoices for the A/P department; maintain calendar of all daily interpreting schedules; Bi-weekly payroll reconciliation using Kronos time and attendance system to reduce payroll errors and increase data accuracy; track leave balances

Branch Product Manager

TTI, Inc - February 1999 to August 2002

Duties include but were not limited to:

Acted as liaison between manufacturer representatives and branch sales representatives; Negotiated prices to yield highest possible gross profit; Built effective relationships with all manufacturer representatives to foster goodwill for company; Interfaced with manufacturer representatives to avert and resolve issues; Conducted training session to upgrade sales representative product knowledge; Provided technical product knowledge for sales representatives with cross-reference material; Provided current manufacturer product and price catalogues to sales representatives; Maintained and updated manuals of ship and debits by customer; Researched competitor products, policies and pricing; Participated actively in company total quality process; Acquired market share data from manufacturer representatives and suppliers; Reads, analyze and interprets business periodicals, professional journals, technical procedures and governmental regulations; Writes reports, correspondence and procedure manuals; Analyzes impact of decisions before execution; Calculates discounts, interest, commissions, proportions and percentages

TTI, Inc - Columbia, MD - February 1993 to August 2002

Branch Product Manager Assistant / Customer Service Representative

TTI, Inc - 1997 to 1999

Duties include but were not limited to: Supported Branch Product Manager and Sales Representatives; Expedited orders/shipments from manufacturers and/or customers; Resolve customer concerns (i.e. issues, problems)

Administrative Assistant

- 1993 to 1997

General administrative duties

EDUCATION

Customer Service

CATONSVILLE COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Baltimore, MD December 2012

Certification

ANNE ARUNDEL COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Hanover, MD December 2011